A Finding Aid to the Evangeline J. Montgomery Papers, 1928-2018, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Professional Activity Files, 1963-2017; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 7.6 Linear feet Boxes 4-11
  - Metal Arts Guild, 1969-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Mini Art Gallery Committee, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - National Association of Negro Business and Professional Women's Club (NANBPWC), 1975-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6-9)
  - National Conference of Artists, "15 Michigan Artists", 1987; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) Copies (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - National Conference of Artists, Awards, 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - National Conference of Artists, Detroit, circa 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - National Conference of Artists, Montgomery and Floyd Coleman Interview, 2001; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 19-21)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 22-23)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 9-12)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 13-16)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 2000-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 2002; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - National Conference of Artists, General, 2000-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Oakland Museum, Black Artists Exhibition Survey, 1970-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
  - Oakland Museum, Grafton Tyler Brown Catalog Statement Drafts by Montgomery, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Oakland Museum, General, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 6-10)
  - Oakland Museum Archives, Harry S. Richardson, 1963-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Parting Ways, The Museum of Afro-American Ethnohistory, Inc., 1977-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Program Consultant, Afro-American Historical and Cultural Museum (Philadelphia), 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Project Materials, General, 1971-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Project Proposals, circa 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Proposals were not created by Montgomery.
  - Rainbow Sign, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
  - Receipts, 1969-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Rhode Island Black Heritage Society, circa 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - San Francisco Art Commission, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 20-21)
  - Southern Arts Federation, 1981-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Thirdworld Museum / Black Cultural Endowment, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - United States Information Agency (USIA), circa 1985-2008; Archival Resource Key; Includes 4 sound cassettes and 1 video cassette (VHS). (Box 11, Folder 1-12)
  - Women's Caucus for Art (WCA), General, 1991-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Women's Caucus for Art (WCA), Awards Banquet, 1999; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Women's Caucus for Art (WCA), June Wayne Address, 1999; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - The Year of American Craft Executive Committee, 1989-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Research Files and Notes, 1928-2018; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 4 Linear feet Boxes 11-16, 26
  The series contains Montgomery's files on subjects she researched over her multi decade long career as an arts administrator. Included is material on African and African American arts and history, Black media, Black photographers, the museum profession, and artists. Artists included in Montgomery's research are Betye Saar, Lois Mailou Jones, Nike Davies-Okundaye, Romare Bearden, Ruth Waddy, Sam Gilliam, and significant files on Sargent Johnson, most of which were most likely created while curating Johnson's retrospective in 1971 for the Oakland Museum. The files consist of 29 sound and video recordings, 3 born digital records, printed materials, notes, artists' biographical materials, correspondence, and other material related to her research subjects. Also included are notes on printmaking, twins, and grants, as well as three notebooks regarding projects, travel plans, and other professional activities.
  - African and African American Arts, Dr. Tritobia Benjamin Motley Series, 1992; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - African and African American Arts, Music, circa 2000s; Archival Resource Key; 3 Electronic discs (CD) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - African and African American Arts, Nigerian Art, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (U-matic) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - African and African American Arts, Royce Vaughn "An Afro American Thing", 1995; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) Includes description of recording. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - African and African American Arts, "Slave Quilts with Raymond Dobard", 1989; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - African and African American Arts, General, circa 1969-circa 1995; Archival Resource Key; Includes 1 video recording (VHS). (Box 12, Folder 5-8)
  - African and African American History, circa 1969-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 9-11)
  - Artists, Alvin Carter, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Artists, Alyce Smith-Cooper, 1985-1997; Archival Resource Key; Includes 1 video recording (VHS). (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Artists, Betye Saar - General, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Artists, Betye Saar - Lecture at National Conference of Artists, 1988; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Artists, Betye Saar - "Connections: Installations in Southeast Asia", 1988; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Artists, Betye Saar - Interview, circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Artists, Howard Smith, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Artists, Jacob Lawrence, circa 1980-circa 1998; Archival Resource Key; Includes 1 video recording (VHS). (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
  - Artists, John Biggers / Hampton University, 2001; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Artists, Lois Mailou Jones, 1971-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 6-8)
    Includes an interview by Montgomery and 2 video recordings (VHS).
  - Artists, Nash Porter - "New Orleans Now", circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Artists, Nike Davies-Okundaye (Twins Seven Seven; Olaniyi), 1981-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Artists, Romare Bearden, 1971-2003; Archival Resource Key; Includes 2 sound cassettes for the exhibition The Painted Sounds of Romare Bearden. (Box 13, Folder 11-12)
  - Artists, Ruth Waddy, 1969-2018; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Artists, Samella Lewis - "The collection of Samella Lewis and Selected Works by Samella Lewis", circa 1999; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Artists, Sam Gilliam, 1991-1998; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 13, Folder 15-16)
  - Artists, Sam Gilliam - "Of Fireflies and Ferris Wheels", 1991; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (U-matic) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - Articles, 1935-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 2-3)
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - Articles, 1928-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - Copies of Birth and Death Records, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - Copies of Photographs of Artwork, circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - Copyright, circa 1971-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - Correspondence, 1944-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1971-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - Notes and Writings, 1964-circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 10-15)
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1939-circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 16-17)
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - Portraits and Personal Photographs, circa 1935-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - Retrospective Exhibition, 1952-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 19-23)
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - Scrapbooks, 1929-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1-7)
    7 scrapbooks
  - Artists, Sargent Johnson - General, 1938-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 8-11)
  - Artists, Shirley Woodson, 1985-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Artists, General, circa 1965-2005; Archival Resource Key; Includes 3 sound cassettes and 1 mini cassette labeled "Margo Humphry Oct. 6, 1988," "David [McDonald]," "Martha Jackson Jarvis," and "Wini Owens." (Box 15, Folder 13-18)
  - Black Media, circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Black Photographers, 1968-2002; Archival Resource Key; Includes 5 sound cassettes. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Evans-Tibbs Collection, circa 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Housing Redevelopment, 1980-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Museum Profession, 1979-2000; Archival Resource Key; Includes 1 video recording (VHS). (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
  - Notes, General, 1968-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 7-9)
  - Notes on Grants Received, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Notes on Printmaking, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Notes on Twins, circa 2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Notebooks, circa 1973-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 13-15)
    3 notebooks with notes regarding projects, travel plans, Montgomery's exhibitions, and other professional activities.
  - Writing, Play and Poetry, circa 1948-circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 16-17)
- Files Regarding Montgomery's Career as an Artist, 1970-2016; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 16-17
  The series documents Montgomery's career as an artist, particularly her printmaking and metal work. Files include 4 sound and video recordings, artwork and price lists, loan records, sales and consignment records, certificates of authenticity, artwork donations, and interviews with Montgomery for The Historymakers series and with art historian Floyd Coleman. Files for the Brandywine Workshop include material from Montgomery's award for Excellence in the Arts in 2004 and her residency at the workshop in 2006. Files for exhibitions include artwork lists, loan documents, and photograph albums of Montgomery's exhibitions.
  - Ancestral Boxes and Bronze Work, circa 1995-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Artists' Cards, 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 19)
    Montgomery's artwork is included as part of the artists' card project.
  - Artist Statements, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Artwork Lists, 1998-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Certificates of Authenticity for Montgomery's Artwork, 1997-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Donations of Montgomery's Artwork, 2002-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Donation and Grant, D.C. Commission on the Arts and Humanities Art Bank Collection, 2010-2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Brandywine Workshop, 1990-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 25-26)
  - Brandywine Workshop, 1990-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Brandywine Workshop, James Van Der Zee Awards, 1995-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Exhibitions, 1970-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 3-8)
  - Exhibitions, Photo Albums, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 9-11)
  - Exhibitions, Watergate Gallery, 2014-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - General, 1973-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 13-14)
  - Interview with Montgomery and Floyd Coleman, 2000; Archival Resource Key; 3 Sound cassettes (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Interview with Montgomery for The Historymakers, 2004; Archival Resource Key; Includes 1 video recording (VHS). (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Loans, 1974-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Permission Agreements, 2010-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Price Lists and Sales Records, 1998-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Project, Art Cart: Saving the Legacy, 2012-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Project, Printmaking Legacy Project, 2010-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Sales and Consignments, 2008-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Scrapbook, 1974-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Typescript, "Explorations of Identity and Cultural Memory: The Art and Life of Evangeline Juliet Montgomery" by Floyd Coleman, 1994-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 24)
    Includes notes and correspondence with Montgomery. Article was printed in The Crisis magazine in 2000.
- Printed and Documentary Materials, 1964-2018; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 7.2 Linear feet Boxes 17-23, 26, OVs 27-29, 31-34
  Printed material regarding Montgomery and her career as an artist, curator, and administrator includes artwork reproductions, clippings, posters, and exhibition announcements and catalogs. Other materials include brochures and pamphlets, booklets, event programs, invitations, journals and magazines, press releases, publicity packets, and reports. Also included are 3 video recordings of documentary material regarding woodturning, David Dorfman Dance, and American glass.
  - Art Reproductions, Montgomery's Artwork, circa 2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Art Reproductions, circa 1970s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Art Reproductions, circa 1990s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Art Reproductions, circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Book Covers, circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 27)
  - Booklets, circa 1970-circa 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 2-10)
  - Brochures and Pamphlets, circa 1970-circa 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 11-15)
  - Calendar, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Calendar, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, Montgomery, circa 1970-circa 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 17-19)
  - Clippings, Montgomery's Contributions in Bayviewer Magazine, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, circa 1970-circa 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, circa 1970-circa 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 1-9)
  - Clippings, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Documentary Video Recordings, 1992-1996; Archival Resource Key; 3 Videocassettes (VHS) Notes on cassettes: "Woodturners," "David Dorfman Dance," and "American Glass." (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Event Programs, circa 1965-2018; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 11-14)
    Program in folder 13 for Howard University's 119th Convocation contains signatures from Lois Mailou Jones and others.
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Montgomery, 1968-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 15-17)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Montgomery, 1968-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Others, circa 1971-2017; Archival Resource Key; Includes 1 electronic disk (CD). (Box 20, Folder 3-18)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Others, circa 1971-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 1-12)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Others, 1972-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Flyers, 1996-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Flyers, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Greeting and Post Cards, circa 1970-circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Invitations, 1964-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 15-17)
  - Journals, 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Journals, 1971-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 1-5)
  - Magazines, 1972-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 6-10)
  - Newsletters, 1972-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 11-13)
  - Portfolio, Black Artists in America, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Posters, Montgomery Exhibitions, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 28)
  - Posters, Other Exhibitions, 1970s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 29)
  - Posters, Other Exhibitions, 1970s-2007; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 31)
  - Posters, Other Exhibitions, 1992-2008; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 33)
  - Posters, Other Exhibitions, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 34)
  - Posters, General, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Posters, General, 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 32)
  - Postage Stamps, circa 1980s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Press Releases, circa 1970s-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Publicity Packets, 1977-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 16-18)
  - Reports, 1969-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 19-20)
  - Reports, 1969-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Artwork, circa 1957-2006; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Boxes 23, 26, OV 30
  The series contains mixed media artwork by Montgomery, drawings and sketches, a print by Suzanne Browne, and three sketchbooks containing sketches for Montgomery's design project at Los Angeles City College, another student sketchbook possibly created by Montgomery, and a sketchbook containing a child's drawings.
  - Mixed Media by Montgomery, 2005-2006; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Drawings for Cufflinks, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Drawings and Sketches, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Print by Suzanne Browne, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 30)
  - Sketchbook, Child's Drawings, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Sketchbook, Design Project at L.A. City College by Montgomery, circa 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 8)
    Sketchbook possibly belonging to Montgomery as a student.
- Photographic Materials and Moving Images, circa 1965-2017; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 3 Linear feet Boxes 23-26, OV 27
  The series contains photographic prints, slides, transparencies, and digital photographs of Montgomery; friends and colleagues; 5 born digital records of works of art by Montgomery and others; photographic prints of Mardi Gras Indians by J. Nash Porter; White House photographs; photographs of artist Royce Vaughn; 2 personal video recordings; personal snapshots that include 33 photographs albums of family and friends, social gatherings, Montgomery's exhibition openings, and other personal events; and events and exhibitions that includes 3 video recordings of the Wembley Music Festival, African American historical events, and the funeral of Ron Brown.
  - Montgomery, 1962-circa 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Montgomery with Others, circa 1970-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Montgomery with Others, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Montgomery with Others by Sonnie B. Mason, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Montgomery and Susan Goldman / Slides of Goldman's Works of Art, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Others, Mardi Gras Indians by J. Nash Porter, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Others by Roy Lewis, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Others, of Royce Vaughn, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Others, White House Photographs, 1993-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 13)
    Photographs may have been taken by White House photographer Sharon Farmer.
  - Others, 1967-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Events and Exhibitions, circa 1970-circa 2010; Archival Resource Key; Includes 3 video recordings (VHS). (Box 23, Folder 15-22)
    Video recordings consist of 2 cassettes of the Wembley Music Festival and 1 cassette labeled "Ron Brown Funeral" and "African American Historical Events." Also included in the files are photographs by Lillian J. Hoffler of Lowry Sims and David Driskell, the opening ceremony of the Charles H. Wright Museum of African American History in Detroit, and Dianne and Carnell Locke's 25th anniversary party by John Woe.
  - Personal, circa 1965-circa 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Personal Recordings, 1988-2002; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) Labels on cassettes indicate that ice skating and Debi Thomas are featured in the recordings. (Box 23, Folder 24-25)
  - Personal Snapshots, 1980s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 1-13)
  - Personal Snapshots, Photo Albums, 1980s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 14-18)
    10 albums
  - Personal Snapshots, Photo Albums, 1980s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 1-13)
    23 albums
  - Works of Art, Montgomery, circa 1965-2017; Archival Resource Key; Includes 5 electronic discs (DVD). (Box 25, Folder 14-15)
  - Works of Art, Arthur Carraway, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Works of Art, Benny Andrews, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Works of Art, Jene Ballentine, circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Works of Art, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 19)
    Original container labeled "NCA."
  - Works of Art, circa 1970s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 20)
    Includes photograph of Sheryle Butler.
  - Works of Art, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 27)
- Unidentified Audiovisual Material, circa 1990s; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 1 Folder
  The series consists of 2 sound recordings and 2 video recordings having no description or label is illegible.